When our flag falls our nation will rise.
Olympus Has Fallen is a action, thriller film directed by Antoine Fuqua.
When the White House (Secret Service Code: "Olympus") is captured by a terrorist mastermind and the President is
kidnapped, disgraced former Presidential guard Mike Banning finds himself trapped within the building.
As the national security team scrambles to respond, they are forced to rely on Banning's inside
knowledge to help retake the White House, save the President and avert an even bigger disaster.
Mike Banning, played by Gerard Butler.
President Benjamin Asher, played by Aaron Eckhart.
Connor, played by Finley Jacobsen.
Forbes, played by Dylan McDermott.
Kang, played by Rick Yune.
Alan Trumbull, played by Morgan Freeman.
Olympus Has Fallen is a 2013 American political action thriller film directed and co-produced by Antoine Fuqua from a screenplay
written by Creighton Rothenberger and Katrin Benedikt, and is the first installment in the Has Fallen film series.
The film stars Gerard Butler (who also co-produced), Aaron Eckhart, and Morgan Freeman with Angela Bassett, Robert Forster,
Cole Hauser, Ashley Judd, Melissa Leo, Dylan McDermott, Radha Mitchell, and Rick Yune in supporting roles.
The plot depicts a North Korean-led guerrilla assault on the White House, and focuses
on disgraced Secret Service agent Mike Banning's efforts to rescue U.S.
President Benjamin Asher.
The film was released in the United States on March 22, 2013, by FilmDistrict,
and grossed $170 million against a $70 million production budget.
The film received mixed reviews from critics, who praised Fuqua's direction and
Butler's performance, but criticized the overt violence and the screenplay.
Olympus Has Fallen was one of two 2013 films that depicted a terrorist attack against the White
House; the other was White House Down, which was released three months later.
A sequel, titled London Has Fallen, was released on March 4, 2016,
with the principal cast members reprising their roles.
A third film, Angel Has Fallen, was released on August 23, 2019.
The film explores themes of usa president, washington dc, usa,
the white house, secret service, terrorist attack.
The tone is intense.